[SOUND] So, data visualization can consist of some very simple charts,
[音乐] 所以 数据可视化可以包含好几种简单图表
but the success of a data visualization can often depend on how
但成功的数据可视化则常常
we map our data variables to the elements of those charts.
取决于我们如何把数据变量映射成为图表中的元素
So we can start with a Bar Chart.
我们从柱状图开始
And the bar chart has two axises typically.
柱状图一般有两个坐标轴
You've got a horizontal axis and a vertical axis.
一个水平轴和一个数值轴
And you're usually measuring discrete values here, and
水平轴常常是离散数值
some either discrete or continuous value vertically.
竖直轴可能是离散的 也可能是连续的
And this benefits from the fact that you're mapping a variable,
当你映射一个变量
a data variable, to both position, the actual height of these bars,
一个数据变量 到图表的具体位置上时 要根据数据本身考虑柱形的实际高度
as well as to a length, the size of the bar.
以及其宽度 尺寸
And so you do a really good job of not only seeing.
这样才是好的数据可视化 而不仅仅是视觉感知
That, for example, the orange bar is larger than the blue bar, but
比如 橙色的柱形比蓝色柱形要高
how much larger the orange bar is to the blue bar because
但究竟高出多少？
position and length are both at the top of perceptual effectiveness for
对于从视觉角度展示经过量化的数值而言
displaying quantitative values.
位置和尺寸都是非常重要的
And so usually vertically we have some sort of quantitative dependent variable.
所以 我们常常在竖直方向上放上与数值有关的变量
And then horizontally these can be categories.
而水平方向则放置分类
And so we have some nominal variable or at least some discreet variable here
这样 （水平方向上）我们就有一些标度量 或者说 至少是一些离散的量
indicating the individual bars that we're plotting.
来标示每个柱形的意义
And this is an independent variable, a dimension.
这也是一个独立变量 一个维度
And then this is some kind of measure of that dimension.
这个变量用以测量这个维度
It's a dependant variable depending on the value of this independent variable.
它是个依赖于这个独立变量的变量
Similarly, you have a line chart.
与之相似的是线形图
A line chart has data points that are connected by a line.
线形图里的数据点之间用线连接
And so this is very very similar to a bar chart.
所以 这和柱状图非常非常相似
These data points are at the same altitude as the tops of the bars.
这些数据点和柱状图的数据点一样高
So they benefit from position but they don't have the length.
它们具有位置方面的表达 但不像柱状图里那样
That you visually see with the bars in a bar chart.
它们没有长度方面的视觉表达
So you still do a pretty good job of
在区分不同量化数值和数值关系的方面
being able to discern quantitative values and their relationship of quantitative
线形图中用不同高度的数据点来表示的方法
values in the altitudes of these data points in a line chart.
依然很有效
And so again we have a quantitative dependent variable vertically that's
这样我们就有一个 竖直方向上连续的因变量
changing based on some quantitative independent variable horizontally.
它的变化是基于一些 水平方向上的独立变量而变化的
But now the horizontal value is some quantitative continuous variable and
但现在水平轴上的值是连续的量
the vertical value also needs to be a quantitative continuous variable
而竖直方向上的值也需要是连续的
because we're drawing lines between these data points and these lines imply
因为我们把数据点连成了线 这意味着
that there's a continuity of values between these data points and
数据点之间有连续的值的变化
these data points have a horizontal and a vertical component.
而且因为这些点都有水平和数值上的分量
These lines have a horizontal and vertical component.
这些线条也有水平和竖直的分量
So you don't want to use a line chart to display data across categories because
所以不要用折线图去表现不同类别的数据
that's implying that there's in between values in between these categories and
因为这表示分类之间还有其他值
if they're nominal categories, if they're discreet,
但如果它们是离散的分类
then there should not be in between values.
分类之间不应该有值
Your visualization shouldn't imply that there's in between being values.
你的可视化结果就不应该表现它们之间有数据点存在
If we remove the lines, we get a scatter plot.
如果我们把连线去掉 就会得到散点图
And a scatter plot gives us some other flexibility.
散点图可以在其他方面灵活表达
When we display a line plot, we're displaying a function.
当我们展示线图时 我们展示的是一个函数
We're displaying some dependent variable
我们展示了一些因变量
that's changing according to an independent variable.
它们根据自变量而改变
So that there's one dependent value for every independent value.
对于每个自变量而言 都有对应的因变量
So there's basically one measure for each change in dimension.
所以 对每个维度的变化 我们都有一相应的量度
When we do a scatter plot, we have two independent variables so
画散点图时 我们有两个独立变量
that I can have the same horizontal value here and
也就是说 可以有两个点有相同的水平轴值
I can have two values associated with that and so that can be a powerful value.
可以有两个值与同一个水平轴坐标对应 这样的表达很强大
You usually don't connect these with a line unless there is some order in
你一般不会把它们连起来 除非数据来源本身
which the data is coming in that you want to associate with a line and
存在次序关系 你想要用线条来表达
that would be an additional dimension you could indicate on a scatter plot.
如果那样的话 这就是散点图中的另一个维度
But the line doesn't infer that you're plotting a function, because
但线条并不代表你描述了一个函数关系
a scatter plot doesn't plot a function unless the data's organized that way.
因为散点图本身没有函数 除非数据本身就是按函数关系组织的
And so you have two independent variables, a horizontal independent variable and
所以你就有两个独立变量 水平轴上的自变量
a vertical independent variable.
和竖直轴上的因变量
And you're getting an indication of position, both, horizontally and
而且你也从点的位置 在水平方向的位置 垂直方向的位置
vertically, for the quantitative values on each of the two axes.
看出数据点在坐标轴上对应的数量关系
You also get some cues based on density if these points tend to cluster in certain
如果这些点会聚集在某些特定区域的话
areas.
你还能看出密度的分布
You can also create a Gantt Chart,
你还可以画甘特图
which is kind of looks like a sideways bar chart, except the bases of objects don't
看起来像是横向的柱形图 但甘特图中 柱形不会像排队那样
line up with one of the axises like they would in a bar chart.
底部排在坐标轴上 这和柱形图中不同
And so in this case, we have two independent variables,
在这个例子中 我们有两个独立变量
things that are no longer related as a function, but
它们不再有函数关系
you still get the benefits of position and length.
但你还是可以从中得到 位置和长度的信息
Gantt charts are usually processed diagrams that tell you
甘特图常用来表示
the various stages of a project.
一个项目的不同阶段
And so horizontally a Gantt chart would usually be some display of time.
甘特图常常用水平轴代表时间
This may be a quarter, or date, or some other time axis.
单位可能是一季度 日期等等
And then vertically, this is some categorical, often a discrete or nominal
竖直方向上是一些分类 常常是离散的值 或者类别名称
independent variable here vertically, and this is typically the tasks.
一般用来标注任务
So you'll have the first tasks and then the second task, and
这样你就有任务一 任务二
the second task may start before the first task finishes.
任务一还没结束 任务二也可以就开始
And tasks may stop and then start up again, and so you get this overlap.
任务也可以暂停 过段时间再继续 这样就得到了这种任务重叠
Again, it benefits from both position and length.
和之前一样 这也可以让你从位置和长度中得到信息
but it operates from two independent variables.
但它表现的是两个独立变量
Again one could be quantitative and one could be nominal similarly to a bar chart.
和之前一样 一个是数值的量 另一个是类别量 这和柱状图相似
But in a bar chart you have one dependent variable
但在柱状图里有一个因变量
plotted over an independent variable.
这个因变量根据自变量的值变化
In a Gantt chart you have to independent variables And, finally, you have a table.
而在甘特图里有两个自变量
In this case, you have two nominal variables, two categories,
最后 来看表格 在表格中 你有两个类别量 即两个分类
for example, they're independent variables.
比如说 这两个量相互独立 都是自变量
One doesn't depend on the other necessarily and
两个量不一定相关
you're just looking at two separate dimensions, and
你看到的只是两个独立的维度而已
in plotting some value that would be the entry in each of these table entries.
如果要作图的话 要画出表内所有的条目才行
So it really benefits from position only, and again, that position is discrete or
所以这个只能通过位置来表达信息
nominal.
而位置是一个离散量 或者是一个表示类别的量
It's not a continuous position, as it would be in a scatter plot.
位置不是连续的 象散点图一样
It's in discrete, quantized regions.
表格表示里只有离散化的区块
You might also notice if you look at this long enough,
你可能也会注意到 如果你盯着看的时间很长
you can see some flashing happening at the intersections.
你可以看到缝隙的交叉点在闪烁
And it's, again, important to remember your perceptual psychology
这需要你回忆一下前面认知心理学到的内容 重要的是
to know when you're laying these things out to pay attention to
象这样的布局 当你专注这些（颜色）反差的时候
contrast to make sure that you don't get some unwanted perceptual features.
注意不要被那些不相关的认知特性所分散
So here's a table that visualizes the decision
这里有张表 展示的是
you need to make of what chart to use in various situations,
在各种不同的场景下 如何根据你要显示的数据
depending on the data that you want to display.
来选择图表类型
Very often you have at least one independent variable and then you
一般情况下 你至少有一个独立变量
may have a dependent variable on it or you may have an independent variable.
你可能有一个依赖于它的因变量 也可能有另一个独立变量
And your independent variable might be discreet or nominal, some category,
你的独立变量可能是离散的 或者是代表类别的名称量
or it might be some some quantity tha varies continuously and
也可能是连续的
your dependent value could similarly be continuous or discrete, or an independent
与之类似 你的因变量也可能是连续 或者离散的
variable could be a category, or it could be a continuously changing value.
或者 另一个独立变量可能也是个类别量 或者是个连续的不断变化的量
Independent of your horizontal axis, and so depending on each
与水平坐标轴无关 而是根据数据的特性 可相应选择表中的图形方式
of these configurations you could look up in this table which you want to use.
你都可以在这张表上找到 你应该用什么图表比较合适
If you have an independent variable and
如果你有一个自变量
a dependent variable, then most often you want to use a bar chart.
和一个因变量 一般你会想用到柱形图
You can use a line chart, but only when you have a continuous dependent variable
你也可以用线形图  但只有当 因变量和自变量的值
and a continuous independent variable, because the lines indicate
都连续变化时才可以 因为连线意味着
that they're in between values both horizontally and vertically.
两个数据点之间也有值 在水平和竖直方向都是如此
You want to use a Gantt chart if you have a independent variable.
当你有一个水平轴上连续的自变量 加上一个可以表示在竖直轴上的类别量
That's continuous and a categorical axis vertically or
或者 一个竖直轴上的连续量 加上一个水平轴上的类别量
a categorical axis horizontally and a continuous value vertically.
你就可以用甘特图
Either one of those will form a Gantt chart.
其中的组合之一 都可以生成甘特图
If you have two categorical axes, you want to make a table.
如果你有两个分类轴 那么最好用表格
And if you have two continuous axes that are both independent,
如果两个轴都是连续的独立变量
you want to make a scatter plot.
用散点图会很适合
So we use the kind of data that we're trying to visualize nominal,
总而言之 我们根据所使用的数据 来决定图表类型
ordered, quantitative, whether it's continuous,
数据可能是连续的、离散的
whether it's discreet, whether variables are dependent or independent.
可能是因变量也可能是自变量
To not only figure out how they map to chart elements, but
据此 我们不仅要弄清楚数据 和图表元素之间的对应关系
more importantly to decide which chart best displays them.
更重要的是 决定怎样的图表可以 以最佳方式体现它们
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community